Finding Aid for the Alec Hyatt King Papers, 1859-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Published writings by King and others, 1892-1993, I; Folder 1-246
  - Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966 Music and music printing in incunabula, 1932., Published in Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, v. 26 (1932) Appears to be C.B. Oldman’s copy. Includes letter to A.F. Johnson at the British Museum from Stanley Morr..[illegible] (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Kirby, Tim Setting the right note, 1982., Published in British printer (January 1982) (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Knapp, J. Merrill Autograph manuscripts of Handel's Ottone, 1972., Published in Festschrift Jens Peter Larsen (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Knapp, J. Merrill Hall Handel collection, 1974., Published in Princeton University Library Chronicle, v. 36, no. 1 (Autumn 1974) (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Köhler, Karl-Heinz, 1928- Musikabteilung, 1961., Published in Deutsche Staatsbibliothek 1661-1961. Bd. 1. Geschichte und Gegenwart. (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Krause, Peter Handschriften der Werke Johann Sebastian Bach in der Musikbibliothek der Stadt Leipzig, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Krause, Peter Handschriften und ältere Drucke der Werke Georg Friedrich Händels in der Musikbibliothek der Stadt Leipzig, 1966. (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Krautwurst, Franz Heilsbronner ChorbÜcher der Universitätsbibliothek Erlangen (Ms. 473, 1-4), 1965., Published in Jahrbuch für frankische Landesforschung, Bd. 25 (1965) (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Krummel, Donald William, 1929- Citing the score: descriptive bibliography and printed music, 1985., Published in Paper for the Bibliographical Society, London, December 17, 1985 Photocopy of typescript (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Krummel, Donald William, 1929- Early German partbook type faces, 1985., Published in Gutenbuerg Jahrbuch (1985) (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Krummel, Donald William, 1929- Graphic analysis: its application to early American engraved music, 1959., Published in Notes, v. 14, no. 2 (March 1959) (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Krummel, Donald William, 1929- Oblong format in early music books, 1971., Published in Transactions from the Bibliographical Society The Library (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Krummel, Donald William, 1929- Viva tutti: the musical journeys of an eighteenth-century part song, 1963., Published in Bulletin of the New York Public Library(Jan. 1963) (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Kunst, Jaap, 1891-1960 Origin of the Kemanak, 1960., Published in Bijdragen, tot de taal-, land-, en volkenkunde, Deel 116, no. 2 (1960) (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Kunst, Jaap, 1891-1960 Some sociological aspects of music (lecture given at the Library of Congress, 27 October 1956), 1956. (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Lang, Paul Henry, 1901-1991 Erich Hertzmann (1902-1963), 1963., Published in Musical Quarterly (July 1963) Editorial: Obituary (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Lang, Paul Henry, 1901-1991 Music and history: the eleventh Kenyon lecture November 21, 1952, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Lange, Francisco Kurt, 1903-1997 Os compositors na capitania geral das Minas Gerais, 1965., Published in Revista Estudos Historicos, no. 3-4 (1965) (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Langley, Leanne Musical press in nineteenth-century England, 1990., Published in Notes, v. 46, no. 3 (March 1990) (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 45 Jahre Göttinger Händel-Bewegung, 1965., Published in Festschrift: 50 Jahre Handel-Festspiel (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 Esther und die Entstehung der Händelschen Oratorien, 1963., Published in Festschrift: 50 Jahre Handel-Festspiel (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 Handel studies, 1972., Published in American Choral Review, v. 14, no. 1 (1972) Special issue (complete) (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 Handel traditions and Handel interpretation, 1961., Published in Dansk aarbog for musik forskning (1961) Lecture given June 24, 1959, University of London (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 Händels Weg zum Oratorium und sein Messias, 1960., Published in Festschrift: 50 Jahre Handel-Festspiel (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Larsen, Jens Peter, 1902-1988 Oratorium versus Oper, 1945., Published in Festschrift: 50 Jahre Handel-Festspiel (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - LaRue, Jan, 1918-2004 Parisian brass players, 1751-1793, 1960., Published in Brass Quarterly, v. 3, no. 4 (1960) Written with Brofsky, Howard (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Lebrecht, Norman, 1948- Putting up a good score, 1985., Published in Sunday London Times, Suppl. 17 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Legh, Charles, 1922- Adlington Hall, Cheshire, the home of the Leghs of Adlington, 1950 (reprinted 1963)., Contains section on the organ, installed circa 1670 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Lesure, François Estienne Roger et Pierre Mortier, 1956., Published in Revue de musicologie, v. 38 (July 1956) (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Library of Congress. Classification: Class M, Music; Class ML, Music Literature; Class MT, Musical instruction, 1904., By O.G. Sonneck (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Lichtenwanger, William, 1915-2000 Music of "The Star Spangled Banner" from Ludgate Hill to Capitol Hill, 1977., Published in Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress, v. 34, no. 3 (July 1977) Complete issue (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Lievense, Willy Rondgang door de afdeling Europese muziekinstrumenten, [195-?]., Photocopy of typescript; from Haags Gemeentemuseum (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Lindberg, Folke, 1911 Oct. 16- Bibliografica, 1950., Published in Lars-Erik Larsson och hans concertinor (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Linden, Albert vander, 1913-1977 L'ancien orgue du Palais des Acadèmies, 1955., Published in Bulletin de l'academie royale de Belgique (March 3, 1955) (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Linden, Albert vander, 1913-1977 Manuels scolaires d'histoire de Belgique et l'histoire de la musique, 1949., Published in Revue belge de musicologie, v. 3, fasc. 4 (1949) (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Lipphardt, Walther, 1906-1981 Gesangbuch von J. Eichorn d. ä. Zu Frankfürt an der Oder und seine ältesten Ausgaben, 1968., Published in Jahrbuch für Liturgik und Hymnologie, Bd. 13 (1968) (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Loewenberg, Alfred Early Dutch librettos and plays with music in the British Museum, 1947., 2 copies (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Lowinsky, Edward E. (Edward Elias), 1908-1985 Early scores in manuscript, 1960., Published in Journal of the American Musicological Society, v. 13, no. 1-3 (1960) (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Lowinsky, Edward E. (Edward Elias), 1908-1985 Echoes of Adrain Willaert’s chromatic ‘duo’ in sixteenth- and seventeenth-century compositions, 1968., Published in Studies in music history: essays for Oliver Strunk (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Luther, Wilhelm Martin Die Mikrokopie von Autographen, unica und sonstigen musikalischen WertstÜcken, 1951., Published in Zeitschrift Nachrichten für Dokumentation, Jahrgang 2, Heft 4 (December 1951) (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Luther, Wilhelm Martin Notendruck, 1962., Published in Musik in Geschichte und Gegenwart (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - MacArdle, Donald W. Index to Beethoven's conversation books, 1962. (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Marco, Guy A. Earliest music printers of continental Europe: a checklist of facsimiles illuminating their work, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - MatthaÜs, Wolfgang Beiträge zur Musikgeschichte Bonns in den Jahren 1772-1791, 1967., Published in Bonner Geschichtsblatter, Bd. 21 (1967) (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Meyer-Baer, Kathi, 1892-1977 Musikdruck in Inkunabeln: ein Übersehnes Hilfsmittel zur Beschreibung, 1960., Published in Libri, International Library review and IFLA communications, v. 10, no. 2 (1960) (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Meylan, Raymond, 1924- Mise au point à propos d’une prétendue Mise à jour d’oeuvres perdue de Mozart, 1962., Published in Feuilles musicales, Annee 5, n. 8 (November 1962) Complete issue (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Michalowski, Kornel Katalogi tematyczne: historia i teoria, 1980., Entire book (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Minchin, Leslie T. Lieder without a language barrier! Some suggested texts for the singing of lieder in English, 1982., With letter from Minchin (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Mondolfi, Anna Vita e stile di Francesco Provenzale: la questione dell’Alessandro Bala, 1962., Published in Annuario del Conservatorio di Musica S. Pietro a Majella (1962-63) Transcribed author's name: Anna Mondolfi Bossarelli (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Moser, Hans Joachim, 1889-1967 Musikalische Denkmälerwesen in Deutschland, 1952. (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Murray, Gregory, 1905- Accentual cadences in Gregorian chant, 1958. (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Murray, Gregory, 1905- Authentic rhythm of Gregorian chant, 1959. (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Murray, Gregory, 1905- Gregorian rhythm in the Gregorian centuries, 1957., With letter from Murray, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Murray, Gregory, 1905- Plainsong rhythm: the editorial methods of Solesmes, 1956. (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Music Library Association. Music and libraries: selected papers of the Music Library Association presented at its 1942 meetings, 1943., Edited by Richard S. Hill (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Newman, George Music engraving, undated., Published in Typographien? (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Oldman, C. B. (Cecil Bernard) A Beethoven friendship lost documents recovered, 1936., Published in Music & Letters, v. 17, no. 4 (October 1936) (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Oldman, C.B. (Cecil Bernard) Beethoven's variations on national themes: their composition and first publication, 1951., Published in Music review, v. 12, no. 1 (February 1951) (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Oldman, C.B. (Cecil Bernard) Charles Burney and Louis de Visme, 1966., Published in Music review, v. 27, no. 2 (May 1966) (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Oldman, C.B. (Cecil Bernard) Collecting musical first editions, 1934., Published in New paths in book collecting (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Oldman, C.B. (Cecil Bernard) Compleat music librarian, 1960., Published in Fontes artis musicae(1960) Sent by Cecil Hopkinson; review of Alfons Ott's Die Musikbibliotheken. (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Oldman, C.B. (Cecil Bernard) Francis Cox and his 'fragmenta', 1966., Published in British Museum Quarterly, v. 30, no. 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Ott, Alfons Musikbibliotheken, 1959., Published in Handbuch der Bibliothekswissenschaft, Aufl. 2, Bd. 2 (1959) (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Pastore, Giuseppe A. Arielle co’ Wioline di Antonicco Arefece, 1965., Published in Studi Salentini, fasc. 20 (December 1965) (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Paul, Steven E. Wit and humour in the operas of Haydn, 1982., Published in Internationaler Joseph Haydn Kongress Wien 1982 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Picken, Laurence Ernest Rowland Bach quotations from the eighteenth century, 1944., Published in Music Review, vol. 5, no. 2 (1944) (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Pickett, A. G. (Andrew G.) Preservation and storage of sound recordings, 1959., Written with Lemcoe, M. M. (Meyer Marshall), 1921- (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Pincherle, Marc, 1888-1974 Musical creation, a lecture given at the Library of Congress, 4 October 1960, 1960. (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Plamenac, Dragan, 1895-1983 Another Paduan fragment of trecento music, 1955., Published in Journal of the American Musicological Society, v. 8 (1955) (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Podhradszky, I. Works of Erno Dohnanyi, 1964., Published in Studia musicologica, T. 6, fasc. 3-4 (1964) (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Postolka, Milan, 1932- Liszt a Cechy ve Svetle Korespondence, 1968., Published in Casopos narodniho muzea, R. 132 (1963) (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Postolka, Milan, 1932- Liszt und Böhmen im Spiegel der unveröffentlichten Korrespondenz, 1963., Published in Studia musicologica, T. 5, fasc. 1-4 (1963) (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Postolka, Milan, 1932- Musikerbriefe in der Musikabteilung des Nationalmuseums in Prag, 1975., Published in Beiträge zur Musikdokumentation: Franz Grasberger zum 60. Geburtstag With letter from M. Postolka, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Queens College (New York, N.Y.). Queens College supplement (1966) to the Music Library Association's Check list of thematic catalogues (1954) (Barry S. Brrok), 1966. (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Rackwitz, Werner Johann Friedrich Reichardt und das Handelfest 1785 in London, 1960., Published in Wissenschaftliche Zeitschrift der Martin-Luther-Universitat v. 9, no. 4 (July 1960) (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Rasmussen, Mary Some notes on the articulations in the melodic variation tables of Johann Joachim Quantz’s Versuch einer Anweisung die Flöte traversiere zu spielen (Berlin 1752, Breslau 1789), 1966., Published in Brass and woodwind quarterly, v. 1, no. 1-2 (Winter 1966-1967) (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Rattalino, Piero Processo compositivo nel Don Pasquale di Donizetti, 1970., Published in Nuova rivista musicale italiana, anno 1, no. 1 (January-February 1970) (Box 6, Folder 191)
  - Ray, Anthony Collector examines the 'Flower Bowl' and the 'Musical Entertainer', 1965., Published in Connoisseur (December 1965) Two copies, both inscribed (Box 6, Folder 192)
  - Rehm, Wolfgang Notenschrift and AuffÜhrung: die Rolle der Musikverlage, 1977., Published in Notenschrift und Auffuhrung. Symposion zur Jahrestagung der Gesellschaft für Musikforschung, Munich, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Ricci, Franco Carlo Appunti per una biografia di Francesco Maria Veracini nel bicentenario della morte (1690-1768), 1968., Published in Annuario dell'Academia nazionale di Santa Cecilia, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 194)
  - Riedel, Friedrich Wilhelm Aloys Fuchs als Sammler Bachicher Werke, 1960., Published in Bach-Jahrbuch (1960) (Box 6, Folder 195)
  - Riedel, Friedrich Wilhelm Bibliothek des Aloys Fuchs, 1962., Published in Hans Albrecht in memoriam, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 196)
  - Rimmer, Joan Schotsen in the Netherlands, 1700-1978, 1979., Published in Tijdschrift van de vereniging voor nederlandse muziek geschiedenis, v. 29, no. 1 (1979) (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Roberts, John H. Handel's borrowings from his early works: a study in musical style, 1965., Mimeograph copy of dissertation proposal. (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - Roberts, R. J. (Richard Julian), 1930- John Rastell's inventory of 1538, 1979., Published in Library (6th series), v. 1, no. 1 (March 1979) (Box 6, Folder 199)
  - Rosenthal, Albi, 1914- Catalogue of the loan exhibition of music manuscripts organized in conjunction with the English Bach Festival, 1964, 1964., With clipping (Box 6, Folder 200)
  - Rosenthal, Albi, 1914- Franz Anton und Carl Maria von Weber in der FrÜhgeschichte der Lithographie, 1985., Published in Festschrift Rudolf Elvers zum 60. Geburtstag, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Rosenthal, Albi, 1914- Intriguing copy of Paganini’s ‘Capricci’ and its implications, 1985., Published in Nicolo Paganini e il suo tempo, 1985 With correspondence (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Rosenthal, Albi, 1914- Lagerkataloge des Musickantiquariats Leo Liepmannssohn (1866-1935), 1981., Published in Festschrift Hans Schneider, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Rosenthal, Harold D. Royal Opera House Covent Garden from 1732 to the present day, 1956? (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Rubsamen, Walter H. (Walter Howard), 1911-1973 Ballad burlesques and extravaganzas and Current chronicle: United States, Los Angeles, 1950., Published in Musical Quarterly, v. 36, no. 4 (October 1950) (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Rubsamen, Walter H. (Walter Howard), 1911-1973 Music for ‘Quante bella Giovinezza’ and other carnival songs by Lorenzo de’Medici, 1968., Published in Art, science, and history in the Renaissance, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Rushton, Julian Così fan tutte: Mozart’s serious comic opera, 1993., Published in Studies in Music from the University of Western Ontario, v. 14 (1993) (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - Rushton, Julian Vittima è Idamante: did Mozart have a motive?, 1991., Published in Cambridge Opera Journal, v. 3 (1991) (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Rynne, Etienne Harriet Smithson, the Ennis-born wife of Hector Berlioz, 1969., Published in North Munster Antiquarian Journal, v. 12 (1969) (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Schmidt, Gunther Strukturprobleme der Mehrstimmigkeit im Repertoire von St. Martial, 1962., Published in Musikforschung, Jahrgang 15, Heft 1 (1962) (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Scholderer, Victor, 1880-1971 Printer of Jordanus de Quedlinburg, Strasburg, 1481-1502, 1952., Published in Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, v. 46 (3rd quarter 1952) (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Schrade, Leo, 1903-1964 Unknown motets in a recovered thirteenth-century manuscript, 1955., Published in Speculum, v. 30, no. 3 (July 1955) (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Seeger, Charles, 1886-1979 Music and class structure in the United States, 1957., Published in American quarterly, v. 9 (1957) (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Siegmund-Schultze, Walther Händel als Musikdramatiker, 1954., Published in Wissenschaftliche Zeitschrift der Martin-Luther-Universitat Jahrgang 3, Heft 6 (August 1954) (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Siegmund-Schultze, Walther Händel-Forschung an der Universität Halle-Wittenberg, 1967., Published in Wissenschaftliche Zeitschrift der Martin-Luther-Universitat Jahrgang 16, Heft 2-3 (1967) (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Simoni, Anna E.C. Haarlem’s modest muse: anagrams, their solution, and the truth about a Haarlem worthy, 1977., Published in Quarendo, v. 7, no. 2 (1977) (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Smith, William Charles Dr. James S. Hall: GrÜnder und dirigent der Händel-Gesellschaft von Deal und Walmer, 1969., Published in Festschrift 50 Jahre Gottinger Handel-Festspiele (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Smith, William Charles Händels Leben in England, 1959., Published in Handel-Konferenzbericht (1959) (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Smith, William Charles Händels ‘Rinaldo’: ein Überblick Über die frÜhen Ausgaben, 1958., Published in Handel-Jahrbuch (1958) (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - Smith, William Charles Recently-discovered Handel manuscripts, 1937., Published in Musical times (April 1937) (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Smith, William Charles Samson: die ersten Ausgaben und Händels Verwendung des Trauermarsches, 1957., Published in Handel-Jahrbuch, v. 3 (1957) German translation (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - Smith, William Charles Samson: the earliest editions and Handel’s use of the dead march, 1957., Published in Handel Jahrbuch, v. 3 (1957) English version (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Smits van Waeserberghe, Joseph, 1901-1986 De Numero tonorum litterae episcopi A. ad Coepiscopum E. missae; ac, Commentum super tonos: (ad 1000), 1975., Smits van Waeserberghe is editor of the works by A., Episcopus, 11th cent. And E., Episcopus, 11th cent. (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Smits van Waeserberghe, Joseph, 1901-1986 Tres tractatuli Guidonis Aretini: Guidonis Prologus in antiphonarium, 1975., Smits van Waeserberghe is editor of this work by Guido, d'Arezzo (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Snízková, Jitka Jasná Záre: Wotovaná písen z poloviny 15. století, 1963., Published in Casopis Národniho musea. Oddil ved spolecenskych, v. 132, no. 2 (1963) (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Stadlen, Peter, 1910- Berg’s cryptography, 1980., Published in Alban Berg Studien-Alban Berg Symposion. Wien, 1980. (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Stadlen, Peter, 1910- Composer, 1976., Published in Next year in Jerulaslem: portraits of the Jew in the twentieth century, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Stevens, Denis, 1922-2004 Higher musical education in American universities, 1956., Published in Tempo (Winter 1956) (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Thomson, J. M. Question of authenticity: Alfred Hill, Ovide musica, the Chevalier de Kontski and the Wellington Orchestral Society, 1892-1896, 1980., Published in Turnbull Library Record, v. 13, no. 2 (October 1980) (Box 7, Folder 229)
  - Towneley, Simon, Sir, 1921- Metastasio as a librettist, 1960., Published in Art and ideas in eighteenth century Italy, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 230)
  - Tyson, Alan Clementi’s Viennese compositions, 1781-82, 1966., Published in Music Review, vol. 27, no. 1 (Feb. 1966) (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - Vaughan Williams Memorial Library. Vaughan Williams Memorial Library: the story of the library, its contents, services and classification schemes, 1958., Published in Library leaflet no. 3 (1958) English Folk Dance and Song Society (Box 7, Folder 232)
  - Vaughan, Denis Recognition of the authentic text by the use of alternative type characters in the printing of literary and artistic works, 1962., Published in Droit d'auteur, 75th year, no. 11 (November 1962) (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Ward, John M. (John Milton), 1917- Barley’s songs without words, 1970., Published in Lute society journal, v. 12 (1970) (Box 7, Folder 234)
  - Watanabe, Keiichiro Kopisten der Händel-Handschriften in der Santini-Bibliothek, MÜnster, 1971., Published in Journal of the Musicological Society Japan, v.15, no.4 (1971) (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - Waters, Edward N. (Edward Neighbor), 1906-1991 Autograph musical scores and autograph letters in the Whittall Foundation Collection, 1953. (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Waters, Edward N. (Edward Neighbor), 1906-1991 Music collection of the Heineman Foundation, 1950., Published in Notes, v. 7, no. 2 (March 1950) (Box 7, Folder 237)
  - Weissmann, John S. Oeuvre de Laszlo Lajtha, II, 1968., Published in Etudes finno-ougriennes, Tome 5 (1968) (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - Westrup, J. A. (Jack Allan), 1904-1975 Music - its past and its present, 1963., Lecture given at Library of Congress, September 3, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - White, Eric Walter, 1905-1985 Early theatrical performances of Purcell's operas, 1959., Published in Theatre notebook, v. 13, no. 2 (1959) With correspondence (Box 7, Folder 240)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel Bagpipes for the lord, 1958., Published in Metropolitan of Art Bulletin, v. 16, no. 10 (June 1958) Complete issue (Box 7, Folder 241)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel Curse of Pallas Athena, 1959., Published in Studies in the history of art, dedicated to William E. Suida on his eightieth birthday (Box 7, Folder 242)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel Golden harpsichord and Todini’s Galleria Armonica, 1956., Published in Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, v. 14, no. 5 (February 1956) (Box 7, Folder 243)
  - Wolff, Hellmuth Christian, 1906-1988 Mendelssohn-Bild in Vergangenheit und Gegenwart, 1969., Published in Musa - Mens - Musici. Im Gedenken an Walther Vetter, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 244)
  - Wolff, Hellmuth Christian, 1906-1988 Schumanns 'Genoveva' und der Manierismus des 19. Jahrhunderts, 1969., Published in Beitrage zur Geschichte der Oper, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 245)
  - Zecca-Laterza, Agostina Contributo ad una guida pratica di catalogazione per le biblioteche musicali annesse ai conservatori, 1967. (Box 7, Folder 246)
- Correspondence, 1951-1985, II; Folder 247-279
  Almost all of the correspondence was received with other material. It was removed to form a separate series.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Baron, Hermann January 8, 1964, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 247)
  - Benton, Rita September 4, 1979, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986 April 1, 1958, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - British Museum. Dept. of Manuscripts. December 14, 1963, 1 leaf; Signed "Pamda" (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - British Museum. Dept. of Printed books. November 15, 1966, 1 leaf; Signed "Geoffrey" (Box 7, Folder 251)
  - Brown, Maurice John Edwin March 1, 1969, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 252)
  - Bruckner, Bigenwald, Martha, 1910- 1965, 1 leaf; Removed from Die Anfänge der Leipziger Allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung by Martha Bruckner-Bigenwald; not clear if she wrote this typescript (Box 7, Folder 253)
  - Craggs, Stewart R. February 26-March 1979, 4 leaves; Written on behalf of the Royal Philharmonic Society, with replies (Box 7, Folder 254)
  - Deutsch, Otto Erich, 1883-1967 1967-1968, 3 leaves; Includes obituary (Box 7, Folder 255)
  - Dupont-Danican, Jean François October 5, 1982, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 256)
  - Dworetzsky, Elizabeth January 1, 1971, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 257)
  - Hall, James S. December 5, 1966, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - Heartz, Daniel December 29, 1971, 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 259)